A Guide to the Rockefeller Family and Associates, Edward H. Burdick Management Files FA1160
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family and Associates, Edward H. Burdick Management Files
1924-1992
Rockefeller Archive Center
Burdick, Edward H.
Dilworth, J. Richardson (Joseph Richardson)
FA1160
7.06 Cubic Feet 15 legal document boxes.
15 legal document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research, with selected files restricted as noted, in accordance with the terms of donation of the David Rockefeller estate.
Scope and Contents
Edward H. Burdick served as management staff in the joint-office of J. Richardson Dilworth, and later served as office manager, for the Rockefeller Family and Associates, Room 5600 at Rockefeller Center in New York city.
This collection consists of archives administration files of the Rockefeller family archives, 1956-1986, including the planning, development, and founding of the Rockefeller Archive Center; Budget and analysis documentation; as well as meeting records for the Board of Managers, and later the Board of Directors and associated committees. Also documented are office management, staff directories, efficiency, future of work, and reorganization studies; and select investment files and reports from Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. (RBI), Venrock, and the Associates Captial Fund.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accession 2003:068
- Archives Administration, 1956-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Archives Administration, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Archives Administration, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Archives Administration, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Archives - Rockefeller Archive Center, Rockefeller University, 1974-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Archives - Space, 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Joint Office - Budgets, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Joint Office - Costs, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Budget - JDR 3rd Office, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Storage Space - MOMA - C. E. Siegesmund (CES) File, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Cash Statements, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 127-129 55th Street - Garage, 1924-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Rockefeller Family Joint Office - Analysis - Harper Woodward, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Office Space and Incorporation - CES File, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Office Charts - Transparencies and Originals, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Construction Work - 54th Floor Conversion, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Staff Meetings - Operations Committee Files - CES, 1951-1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Office Surveys - Department Heads - CES, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Rockefeller Brothers Inc. (RBI) - Stock Certificates and Ledger, 1946-1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Rockefeller Brothers Inc. (RBI) - Policy and Procedure Manual - Harper Woodward, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Rockefeller Brothers Inc. (RBI) - By Laws and Charter, 1956-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Rockefeller Brothers Inc. (RBI) - Corporate Documents, 1946-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Certificate of incorporation, by-laws, and other vital records.
- Library - Periodicals Subscribed to, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Hills Realty - Correspondence, Minutes, and Reports, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Vault - Pocantico Estate - CES File, 1950-1961 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - David Rockefeller Estate - Open in 2042
- Meetings - Board of Managers - J. Richardson Dilworth (JRD) File, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Managers, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Managers, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Directors, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Directors, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Directors - Executive Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Meetings - Rockefeller Family and Associates - Board of Directors - Executive Committee, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Cemetery Corp., 1976-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Rockefeller and Company, Inc. - SEC and New York State Registration, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Riverside Church - JDR 3rd Memorial Service, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Pocantico Management Corporation, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Board of Managers - Organization, 1965-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Space - 55th Floor Planning, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Office Study, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Office Studies - Booz Allen, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Staff Professional Commitments - A-Z, 1974-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Staff Meetings, 1972-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Meeting agendas with notes from Edward H. Burdick.
- Budget, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
- Accounting - Administrative, 1966-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Allocations, 1969-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Joint Office Costs - Historical, 1960-1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Audit Committee, 1968-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Power of Attorney (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Restricted - David Rockefeller estate - Open in 2042
- Office Procedures and Practices, Staggered Hours, Summer Hours, 1972-1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Office Structure, 1964-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Office Study, 1976-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
- Office Reorganization, 1965-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Board of Managers, 1965-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Board of Managers - Meetings, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Office Directory - Cousins, 1972-1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Cousins Meetings - Office, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Family Trust, 1979 December 21 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Associates Capital Fund - Apollo Distribution, 1983 June (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Associates Capital Fund - Apple Distribution, 1982 April-May (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Associates Capital Fund - Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Associates Capital Fund - Partnership Agreement, 1979-1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Associates Capital Fund - Performance and Reports to Partners, 1979-1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Associates Capital Fund - Pocantico Fund - Performance and Reports to Partners, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Associates Capital Fund - Discovery Fund, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Associates Capital Fund - Growth Fund, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Associates Capital Fund - Venrock Associates - Performance and Reports to Partners, 1979-1984 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)